# Trio Wibowo

Jakarta, Indonesia • 6282111544757 • triowibowo2810@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/triowibowo/ • triowibowo21.github.io/

### Summary

Data analyst with over 4 years of experience transforming data into insights for decision-making to improve product quality, service delivery, and customer satisfaction metrics. Commit to an analytical course to develop programming skills in SQL, R, and Python, focusing on advanced data manipulation, analysis, predictive modeling, and creating visualization with interactive dashboards.

## **Skills**

- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Google BigQuery
- Programming Languages: Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, SciPy, Scikit-Learn), R (tidyverse, ggplot2), SQL
- BI & Visualization Tools: Looker, Tableau, Metabase, Redash
- Statistic: Data Exploration, Cohort Analysis, Hypothesis Testing (Anova, Chi-Square, T-test, Z-test), Machine Learning
- Other: Confluence, JIRA, Github, Airflow, Data Pipeline, Excel/Spreadsheet, Business Strategies

## **Projects**

#### **Customer Churn Prediction**

April 2024

- Explore and analyze 4,250 customer records with 19 features using Python, generating insights through visualizations with Matplotlib and Seaborn.
- Handle missing values and outliers using Pandas and Numpy, employing feature selection and dimensionality reduction to attain accuracy above 88%.
- Implement and evaluate models to identify churn customers with 98% accuracy, delivering actionable insights and recommendations for customer retention.

### Cyclistic Bike-Share Analysis

August 2023

- Analyzed 5.7M Cyclistic bike share trips using R to get insights on user behavior, supporting strategic decisions.
- Utilized tidyverse and ggplot2 to identify peak times and analyze customer segments (casual riders vs. members) to enhance retention and 15% increase conversion strategies.
- Created an interactive Tableau dashboard to visualize key metrics and track daily/monthly usage trends, improving data
  accessibility for stakeholders and accelerating data-driven decisions by 20%.

## **Work Experience**

## PT Bukalapak.com

Jakarta, Indonesia May 2020 - Present

#### **Data Analyst: Customer Satisfaction**

- Created an automated system to classify users for priority service, reducing churn rate by 25%.
- Collaborated with the product team to implement return process automation, reducing resolution interactions by 60%.
- Worked with the AI team to develop a chatbot and automate phone number change requests, achieving a 46% resolution rate.
- Optimized data models and query logic to improve speed and accuracy in report migration, reducing project time by 20%.
- Designed ERD schemas, ETL workflows, and Tableau interactive dashboards to uncover growth opportunities, driving a 30% increase in data-driven decisions at PT Buka Tumbuh Berbagi (BTB).

#### PT Bukalapak.com

Jakarta, Indonesia

## **Operation Delivery Monitoring**

August 2018 - May 2020

- Used SQL to collect transaction data, speeding up follow-ups with delivery partners on issues by 80% over manual entry.
- Execution of 3000 transactions pending over 5-9 (valid and invalid) per day and ensuring 97% of transactions were solved.
- Provide weekly and monthly reports for evaluation and feedback to delivery partners, providing data-driven insights to enhance transaction processes.

#### **Education**

**IPB** University, Bogor, Indonesia Bachelor of Science in Physics

October 2017

## Certification

Data Science by Binar Academy,
Google Data Analytics Professional by Coursera,
Data Scientist by Digital Talent Scholarship,
Data Management Business Analytics (MBA) by IYKRA,

April 2024 August 2023

1ugust 2023

April 2021

March 2021